Dinesh kumar

MERN Stack Developer

■ dineshkr748199@gmail.com \$\ 8986113306 \$\ \overline{\Omega}\$ Github \$\ \overline{\Omega}\$ India in LinkedIn \$\ \overline{\Omega}\$ Portfolio

About Me

I have worked as a SoftWare Developer for more than a year, and I love creating websites that work well and are fast. I can work on both the parts of a website that users see (frontend) and the parts they don't (backend). I use upto-date tools to make sure people have a smooth experience when they use the websites I build. I know how to use HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, and Node.js to make websites that look good and work well on any device.

Professional Experience

React Js Full Stack Developer, @ Technix Technology 🖸

Jun 2024 – present Patna, India

 Developing and maintaining web applications using React. Collaborating with cross-functional teams to design and implement new features. Ensuring high performance and responsiveness of applications. Working with RESTful APIs and backend services to integrate functionalities.

Software Development Engineer, @ Mypustak.com 🛮

Oct 2023 – May 2024 Kolkata, West Bengal

In few month as a Software developer, I mastered HTML, CSS, and JavaScript,React.js, Next.js collaborating on agile projects. Achieved Projects experience in creating responsive and visually appealing websites.

Education

Master of Computer Applications, Indira Gandhi National Open University Jul 2024 – present Patna, India

Bachlor Of Computer Application, Magadh University Bodhgaya

Aug 2019 – Aug 2022 Gaya, India

Skills

HTML5 | CSS3 | JavaScript | React Js | Next.js | Redux-toolkit | Tailwind CSS |

Bootstrap 5 | Rest Api | MUI | Node.Js | Express.Js | MongoDB | Git | C programming |

HackerRank – 2 Stars

Courses

Full Stack Web Development (MERN), Prepbytes Link 🛮

Mar 2023 - Nov 2023 Gurugram (Haryana), India

Internship

Mobile App Development, Brikbond Shopping App

Dec 2022 - Feb 2023

Tech Stack: Java, XML, Firebase Realtime Database, Firebase Firestore, OTP Verification with Firebase Authentication, Razorpay payment gateway integration etc

• This Android App totally work likes flipcart & Mesho Shopping Apps

Soft Skills

Continuous Learning

Team Collaboration and Communication

Strong Problem-solving Abilities